<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Hey👋!.. I am Gokul</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Hey👋!.. I am Gokul</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 23:28:39 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OLX Clone using Ruby on Rails</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/olx_clone_ror/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 23:28:39 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/olx_clone_ror/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever wondered how platforms like &lt;strong&gt;OLX&lt;/strong&gt; handle ad posts, user interaction, and product management? Well, I built a clone of it using &lt;strong&gt;Ruby on Rails 6&lt;/strong&gt;, packed with features like secure user authentication, ad posting, and smooth listing management.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;📂📑  Explore the code at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Br0k3nh4nd012/sampleOLX--ROR&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Githu Repo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 🔗&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-this-project-is-cool&#34;&gt;Why This Project Is Cool:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic Ad Listings&lt;/strong&gt;: Create, browse, update, or delete ads with ease. Got stuff to sell? Post it! Looking for deals? Browse the listings without any hiccups.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secure User Authentication&lt;/strong&gt;: Integrated &lt;strong&gt;Devise&lt;/strong&gt; for simple and secure user sign-ups, logins, and password resets, keeping your account and data safe while you&amp;rsquo;re exploring and posting.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PostgreSQL Power&lt;/strong&gt;: Using &lt;strong&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/strong&gt; as the database ensures smooth handling of all data, even as the platform grows with new ads and users.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Admin Panel Awesomeness&lt;/strong&gt;: With &lt;strong&gt;ActiveAdmin&lt;/strong&gt;, admins can easily manage users, ads, and flagged content through a simple and powerful dashboard.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soft Deletion with Paranoia&lt;/strong&gt;: Accidental deletions? No problem! &lt;strong&gt;Paranoia&lt;/strong&gt; allows you to recover deleted posts and records—peace of mind for everyone.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-under-the-hood&#34;&gt;What’s Under The Hood?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rails 6&lt;/strong&gt; to power the back end, delivering fast, stable, and scalable code&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Puma&lt;/strong&gt; web server to handle multiple requests and keep everything running smoothly&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/strong&gt; handles all the storage, ensuring the app remains efficient and scalable.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-works&#34;&gt;How It Works:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User Authentication&lt;/strong&gt;: Users sign up or log in using &lt;strong&gt;Devise&lt;/strong&gt; and can create and manage their ads.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Admin Dashboard&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;ActiveAdmin&lt;/strong&gt; lets administrators easily control ads, monitor flagged content, and manage user data.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ad Management&lt;/strong&gt;: Users can manage their ads from posting new items to updating or deleting them—all stored and handled via &lt;strong&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;fun-factor-&#34;&gt;Fun Factor? 💥&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is an excellent example of combining functionality with creativity, making something that’s not just useful, but also fun to build! From the database setup to the sleek user interface, it was an awesome journey of turning a simple idea into a fully functioning, production-ready application.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruby Ipify - Ruby Gem</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/ruby_ipify/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 23:28:39 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/ruby_ipify/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Ruby gem for which use Ipify &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ipify.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;https://www.ipify.org/&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  service to provide the public IP address. A Simple Public IP Address API, Likewise a geographical IP address details API.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Explore at -&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Br0k3nh4nd012/ruby_ipify&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Github Link&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-ipify&#34;&gt;About ipify&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ipify.org/&#34;&gt;Ipify&lt;/a&gt; is the best IP address lookup service on the internet. It&amp;rsquo;s fast, simple, scalable, open source&#xA;Ever needed to get your public IP address programmatically?&#xA;Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re provisioning new cloud servers and need to know your IP &amp;ndash; maybe you&amp;rsquo;re behind a corporate firewall and need to tunnel information&#xA;&amp;ndash; whatever the reason: sometimes having a public IP address API is useful!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
